RESUME OF MDUDUZI SIBISI



Western Cape, South Africa



+27 763142410



mdu.sibisi@zoho.com bearth2501@yahoo.com



GitHub



OBJECTIVE

As a tech writer and software developer, my goal is to create content and software that helps people. I want to help people and make their lives easier, whether it's through software that focuses on the user experience or guides that teach people and businesses how to use software. Ultimately, I want to make technology more accessible and easier to use.

I want to work for a company that makes it easier for me to achieve these goals. Beyond money (although that matters), I want to create high quality products and content that can stand the test of time. In a world where money doesn't' exist, I believe these goals would remain the same.

EDUCATION

2004 – 2008: Sunward Park High School (Nation Senior Certificate)

2009 – 2010: CTI Education Group in Partnership with Cambridge University (Certificate in Information Systems (Software Development))

2010: Oracle Certification in Java Programming

2021: Yoast Block Editor Training Certificate

EXPERIENCE

February 2022 - Current:

Technical Writer • Draft.Dev

As a technical writer for Draft.Dev, my responsibilities include crafting high-quality 1500+ word technical articles for a slew of established clients in the software Industry. Our content typically comes in the form of tutorials, roundups (listicles), reviews and persuasive writing that showcases the capabilities of our clients' products. In addition to written content, I'm responsible for coding accompanying software projects for guides, adding code samples, capturing and annotating screenshots as well as creating diagrams. I also edit and articles when required. I've written content for Bright Data, Snyk, Foxit and Hygraph.

September 2020 - Current:

Technical Writer • WellPCB

As a tech writer for WellPCB, I'm responsible for creating search engine optimized electronic engineering content. Part of my duties include enhancing the quality of published articles. I've mostly written content related to the printed circuit boards and the PCB fabrication process. I've also covered a range of electronic and tech topics including single board computers, microcontrollers, and LED lights.

RESUME OF MDUDUZI SIBSI

Hard Skills:

- Content and Tech Writing
 - o SEO Content Creation ななななな
 - Copywriting ☆☆☆☆☆
- Software Engineering
 - o Java (SE + EE) 公公公公
 - Spring Boot ☆☆☆
 - 。 C# 公公公公公
 - o T-SQL (SQLite, MySQL, and PostgreSQL) ななな
 - o Perl ☆☆☆☆
 - o JavaScript 公公公公
 - o HTML 公公公公公
 - 。 CSS 公公公
 - o MongoDB 公公
 - o Forte 4GL 公公公
 - o Jenkins ☆☆☆☆
 - o Network Administration 公分分分
 - Cybersecurity ☆☆☆☆
 - o Markdown 公公公公公



February 2019 – Current:

Technical Writer • Next Ventures

My responsibilities revolve around developing and writing B2B content for Next Ventures' lofty client list. Part of my duties include copywriting and ensuring content is search engine optimized and easy to consume.

February 2014 – Current:

Freelancer

As a freelancer, I've worked on various short term programming projects as well as tech writing gigs. Despite not being certified or trained in marketing, copywriting, and communications, I managed to land copywriting and content development jobs by leveraging my passion for writing, tenacity as well as technical expertise.

June 2010 - April 2013:

Mid-level System Analyst and Programmer • Corefreight Systems

Mid-level System Analyst/Programmer. Primary responsibilities included software development and programming as well as the modification, installation, and maintenance of Corefreight's logistic software. Secondary responsibilities included cooperation with and support for personnel in resolution of user problems, including provision of Helpdesk and infrastructure support. Tools and applications used included Microsoft SQL Server 2008, Forte 4GL, Java (SE and EE), Maven, NetBeans, and Visual Studio.

ACHEIVEMENTS

Grade 9 Certificate in public speaking

Grade 10 Class Representative

Grade 10 Academic Achievement Badge

Grade 11 Highest Achievement in Life Orientation

REFERENCES

Available upon request